<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">TrainingBuddy</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="welcome_to">Welcome to</string>
    <string name="bmi">BMI</string>
    <string name="bmi_long">Body Mass Index (BMI)</string>
    <string name="exercises">Exercises</string>
    <string name="exercise">Exercise</string>
    <string name="workout">Workout</string>
    <string name="logbook">Log book</string>
    <string name="supplements">Supplements</string>
    <string name="enter_weight">Enter weight(KG): </string>
    <string name="enter_height">Enter height(MET): </string>
    <string name="calculate">Calculate</string>
    <string name="view_bmi_progress_graph">View BMI progress graph</string>
    <string name="your_bmi_is">Your BMI is ...</string>
    <string name="exercise_type">Exercies type: </string>
    <string name="rep_count">Rep count: </string>
    <string name="add_to_stats">Add to stats</string>
    <string name="check_stats">Check stats</string>
    <string name="weight">Weight(KG):</string>
    <string name="bmi_weight_graphs">BMI Weight graphs</string>
    <string name="weight_graph">Weight</string>
    <string name="view_weight_progress_graph">View weight progress graph</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="please_choose_exercise">Please choose the type of exercise for which you want stats.</string>
    <string name="information_and_efects">Information and effects:</string>
    <string name="nutritional_information">Nutritional information:</string>
    <string name="add_new_workout">Add new workout</string>
    <string name="new_workout_name">New workout name:</string>
    <string name="reps">Reps</string>
    <string name="sets">Sets</string>
    <string name="save_workout">Save workout</string>
    <string name="next_step">Next step</string>
    <string name="create_new_workout">Create new workout</string>
    <string name="bmi_below">BMI Below 18.5 = Underweight</string>
    <string name="bmi_healty">BMI 18.5-24.9 = Healthy Weight</string>
    <string name="bmi_overweight">BMI 25-29.9 = Overweight</string>
    <string name="bmi_obese">BMI Over 30 = Obese</string>
    <!-- Supplements -->
    <string name="acai_berry">Acai berry</string>
    <string name="acai_berry_description">Acai berry is a well known power food that helps with both detoxing the body cleaning out all of the bad and at the same time acting as a fat burner. Acai berry cann come in a number of forms including fruit itself and also in drinks however the main way to take it as a supplement is to take it in capsule or pull form.</string>
    <string name="acai_berry_nutritions">2 Tablets 4.000mg Acai Berry Per Serving </string>
    <string name="bcaa_s">BCAA`s</string>
    <string name="bcaa_s_description">BCAA`s are a form of amino acid`s that help the body to do a number of things. The product typically protects muscles in the body from any sort of stress or trauma during heavy exercise. They also help out in the long run on recovery and help to prevent build up of lactic acid.</string>
    <string name="bcaa_s_nutritions">900mg of L-leucine, 450mg of L-isoleucine, 450mg of L-valine, 12mg of Vitamin B6</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_tribulus">Bulgarian tribulus</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_tribulus_description">Bulgarian tribulus is a popular testosterone booster used in bodybuilding. Research claims that studies show up to a 50 percent increase in testosterone levels whilst taking tribulus. This extra testosterone helps to both shed body fat and also to pack on pure lean muscle due to heightened recovery.</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_tribulus_nutritions">Tribulus should be 100 percent pure, do not take the risk of taking bad supplements.</string>
    <string name="cla">Conjugated linoleic acid</string>
    <string name="cla_description">CLA or Conjugated Linoleic Acid as its full name is known is very popular in the bodybuilding world as a fat burner which has receieved a lot of attention and testing. It includes antioxident properties so removes fat from the body along with cholesterol and helps to clean the body up.</string>
    <string name="cla_nutritions">Calories 20, Total Fat	2 g</string>
    <string name="creatine_monohydrate">Creatine monohydrate</string>
    <string name="creatine_monohydrate_description">Creatine is a naturally built chemical made inside of you, creatine monohydrate allows us to add more of  this chemical into out bodys. And of course there is good reason to want to do so, this chemical helps to repare and build muscle which helps speed up a bulking process. This is a similar product to creatine ester ethyl bbut many people prefer to trust monohydrate as it is an older product that is considered to be tried and tested.</string>
    <string name="creatine_monohydrate_nutritions">Calories 5,	Sodium	0 mg, Total Fat	0 g, Potassium	0 mg, Saturated	0 g, Total Carbs 1 g, Polyunsaturated 0 g, Dietary Fiber 0 g, Monounsaturated 0 g, Sugars 0 g, Trans 0 g, Protein 0 g, Cholesterol0 mg.</string>
    <string name="green_tea">Green tea</string>
    <string name="green_tea_description">"Green tea is used as both a fat burner and an anti oxident, it is idely available in most supermarkets or health stores and also contains healing properties. The product has been used for many years by multiple cultures and is considered to be one of the best natural fat burners around.</string>
    <string name="green_tea_nutritions">Green tea contains various compounds such as polyphenols, tannin, theophylline, caffeine, vitamin C and many other organic substance.</string>
    <string name="mass_gainer">Mass gainer</string>
    <string name="mass_gainer_description">"Mass gainer is a supplement that does exactly as it says, the extra caloric intake due to mass gainer allows the taker to put on mass amount of weight. This weight will be hard powerful muscle if worked out hard whilst using the supplement however if the user does not workout hard then the supplement will turn to body fat. These types of products contain a large amount of calories and of which are a high amount of carbs.</string>
    <string name="mass_gainer_nutritions">K cals/K: 1,000k cals, Protein: 50g, Fat:- Of which are saturates 10.4g (From the Milk) - Polyunsaturated Fat: 18g - Omega-6: 2g - MCTs: 7g - Soya Lecithin: 1g, Carbohydrates: 96.2g, Fibre: 3g, Sodium: 907mg, Calcium: 1389mg.</string>
    <string name="nitric_oxyde">Nitric oxyde</string>
    <string name="nitric_oxyde_description">Nitric oxide is used as a powerful pre workout supplement, this is typically taken half an hour before a workout and will help to pump up the user of it. Nitric acid delivers large ammounts of energy and concentration allowing a clean heavy workout session in the gym or at home.</string>
    <string name="nitric_oxyde_nutritions">Per Serving Per 100g, K cals/K 71k cals, Protein1.64g, Fat Trace Trace Carbohydrates 18.5g,- Of which sugars 18.5g, Citrulline Malate 700mg, Tyrosine 700mg, Beta Alanine 350mg, L-Histidine 350mg, Lypodiamine® 350mg, Nicotinamide 285mg, Vitamin C from Ascorbic acid (Antioxidant) 350mg, Alpha-Keto-Glutarate 1500mg, Green tea Ext 40% 140mg, Taurine 1500mg, L- Glutamine 2100mg, L-Valine 56mg, Caffeine 200mg, Creatine Monohydrate 2100mg, Calcium from calcium citrate 118mg, Potassium from Potassium citrate 118mg, L-Isoleucine107mg 324mgL- Leucine 140mg, Tri-sodium citrate 140mg, L-Methionine 1500mg, Beta carotene (Antioxidant) 75mg.</string>
    <string name="protein_bar">Protein bar</string>
    <string name="protein_bar_description">A protein bar is an alternative way to ensure that an athlete is getting a good amount of protein per day, they are easy to eat while on the go and relatively cheap if bought in bulk. This protein will be used in post workout to help the recovery process of the body.</string>
    <string name="protein_bar_nutritions">Total Calories: 278.6, Protein: 18.8g, Total Carbohydrates: 34.9g, Sugars: 5g, Dietary Fiber: 2.6g, Fat: 7.1g, Saturates: 3g, Sodium: 75mg</string>
    <string name="whey_protein">Whey protein</string>
    <string name="whey_protein_description">Whey protein is used to fuel your muscles during recovery by feeding them anabolic amino acids.If not used properly then it may cause a build up of fat due to excess calories not being used.</string>
    <string name="whey_protein_nutritions">K cals/K: 146 k cals, Protein: 23g*,Fat: 2.7g of which are saturates: 2.2g, Trans Fat: 0g, Carbohydrates: 11g, Sodium: Trace.</string>
    <string name="zepherine">Zepherine</string>
    <string name="zepherine_description">Zepherine is a new hardcore fat burner used to help the body get rid of excess fat. This product boosts an individuals metabolism allowing them to burn more calories and at the same time suppress there appetite.</string>
    <string name="zepherine_nutritions">320mg Bitter orange, 117mg Caffeine Anhydrous, 20mg Green Tea, 20mg Guarana, 10mg N-Acetyl-L-Carnitine.</string>
    <!-- Exercises -->
    <string name="alternating_crunches">Alternating crunches</string>
    <string name="alternating_crunches_description">Lie the body flat down with a slight bend in your legs. Now lift one side of your upper body whilst lifting the opposite side of your lower body, try to touch your knee with your arm while doing this. Repeat this step on the opposite side of your body.</string>
    <string name="bar_curl">Bar curl</string>
    <string name="bar_curl_description">Choose desired weight on a darbell and move it to waist height. Lift the weight in a curled fashion while the biceps and triceps are kept at a stable position. Lift the bar all the way to shoulder height and then slowly lower the bar before repeating.</string>
    <string name="behind_the_neck_shoulder_press">Behind the neck shoulder_press</string>
    <string name="behind_the_neck_shoulder_press_description">With a normal barbell and a low weight hold the bar infro of your neck with the backs of your hands facing you. Now lift the weight up and extend your arms above your head. Slowly lower the weight behind your shoulders to feel a strong pull before pushing the weight back into the above head position ready for repetition.</string>
    <string name="bench_press">Bench press</string>
    <string name="bench_press_description">Make sure to lie down on the bench in a comfortable position with the back being flat and the bar being lowered enough to be able to extend the arms with ease. Lift the barbell off the rack and move its position forward to be over the chest. Slowly move the barbell down towards the chest, make sure to get as close to the chest as possible for more effect. Finally push the bar back into its original upwards position, make sure to have a spotter during this exercise incase the weight is too heavy to lift back into place.</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_split_squat">Bulgarian split squat</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_split_squat_description">Stand straight with one leg being held back and supported with a bench. Lunge your still standing leg down until you feel a strong pull and then repeat with the opposite leg. </string>
    <string name="chest_press">Chest press</string>
    <string name="chest_press_description">Sit up right with the weight of choose for this movement. Lie down on your back with the dumbells lifted into position by your sides and your arms at a 90 degree angle. Push the dumbells in your hands to extend your arms straight. Lower the dumbell back into position and be sure to hit the 90 degree bend of your arm.</string>
    <string name="crunches">Crunches</string>
    <string name="crunches_description">Lie down on the floor with your legs slightly bent and elevated off the surface, hold your arms in with your hands place on your head. Now move your body in, closing your legs and chest as close together as you can. Then extend the body out again and repeat.</string>
    <string name="deadlift">Deadlift</string>
    <string name="deadlift_description">Bend legs and place hands straight whilst holding the bar, ensure to use a grip that you find comfy along with making sure your bottom is sticking out and your head is facing forward to ensure no damage to the lower back happens. Begin to lift up the bar using your legs, do not move your back and ensure to keep the bottom sticking out, without doing this the lower back risks serious injury. Then allow yourself to slowly move your body up straight and slowly reverse steps to place the weight back down.</string>
    <string name="diamond_push_ups">Diamond push ups</string>
    <string name="diamond_push_ups_description">Spread out your fingers and thumb so that you may connect both hands into a single diamond. Now use this diamond to support your body weight on with your toes supporting the opposite side of your body. Now lower your body down as if doing a standard push up and lift yourself back up again.</string>
    <string name="dish_position">Dish position</string>
    <string name="dish_position_description">Lie down flat relaxing your core. Now bend your legs and your upper body up so that you are in a v shape, hold this shape for an extended duration of time and tense your core.</string>
    <string name="dumbell_curls">Dumbell curls</string>
    <string name="dumbell_curls_description">Hold the dumbells by your side facing forward, make sure they are a sutible weight so it is not hurting to hold them in this position. Now lift them up in a curling fashion, aim to have them parrellel to your shoulders, lower them down after this and repeat.</string>
    <string name="fly_s">Fly`s</string>
    <string name="fly_s_description">Decide on the size of dumbell needed and then sit on the bench upright with them. Lie down the the dumbells in place at your sides. Lift the dumbells up to extend yours arms straight. Slowly lower your arms wide down your body. When you have reached as low as you can then simply lift the dumbells back into the straight extended arms position and repeat.</string>
    <string name="front_squat">Front squat</string>
    <string name="front_squat_description">Approach the bar at a low weight and cross the arms under the bar to allow your hands to touch your shoulders. Remove the bar from the support and move backwards away from the supports way, now lower your body carefully with your bottom sticking out. </string>
    <string name="hammer_curls">Hammer curls</string>
    <string name="hammer_curls_description">Hold a set of dumbells by your side with your arms straight. Lift the weights up without moving the dumbells to the side, make sure your arms are held in tight against the body.</string>
    <string name="mason_twist">Mason twist</string>
    <string name="mason_twist_description">Lie down on your back with your legs bent to allow your feet to stay flat on the floor and a medecine ball or weight being held with your arms. Move your uppper body up into position whilst leaving your feet flat on the floor and legs remaining bent. While keeping your feet and legs in the same position move your arms to once side of your body and attempt to touch the medecine ball to the ground. Repeat this for the opposite side and then repeat the exercise whilst tensing the abs and core.</string>
    <string name="one_arm_tricep_pull_downs">One arm tricep pull downs</string>
    <string name="one_arm_tricep_pull_downs_description">Using a handle attatchment on the cable machine place enough weight to give a resitant weight. Now pull down the weight with your arm and straighten it out as far back as you can, keep your arms in when you do this to give more effect, you should feel a strong pull in the tricep.</string>
    <string name="penguins">Penguins</string>
    <string name="penguins_description">Lie down flat with your legs bent allowing your feet to stand flat on the ground. Keep your lower body in the same position whilst tilting up slightly and reaching over for the tips of your toes by moving to the side. Repeat this on the other side, this will pull abdominal muscles and tighten the core.</string>
    <string name="romanian_deadlift_straight_leg">Romanian deadlift straight leg</string>
    <string name="romanian_deadlift_straight_leg_description">Use low weight and perfrom a normal deadlift with good form to avoid injury. Keep your leg`s straight and your head up. Now make sure to slowly lift the weight down the body while keeping the legs straight at all times. If needed allow the legs to have a light bend but try to avoid it. You should feel a strong pull in your quads. Finally when you have reached as low as your legs will allow, lift the weight back up carefully with good form. </string>
    <string name="russian_twists">Russian twists</string>
    <string name="russian_twists_description">Hold a weight and sit up right with your legs as straight as possible and off the ground. Now keep your legs in the same position whilst moving the weight to one side of your body, try to make the weight touch the ground. Repeat the step for the other side of your body whilst tensing your core.</string>
    <string name="shoulder_press">Shoulder press</string>
    <string name="shoulder_press_description">Hold a comfortable weight dumbell on your legs whilst sitting down on a bench. Now move the dumbells to be parellel just above your shoulders. Push the dumbell weight up to extend the arms and then move back into the parellel position to repeat.</string>
    <string name="shoulder_press_with_bar">Shoulder press with bar</string>
    <string name="shoulder_press_with_bar_description">Choose desired weight and hold it in place slightly infront. Push the weight up until the arms are completly extended, then slowly lower the weight back down into place. </string>
    <string name="shoulder_twists">Shoulder twists</string>
    <string name="shoulder_twists_description">Hold a barbell weight straight in front of your body whilst sitting down. Now lift the weight up twisting it on one side by using just one shoulder to do this. Then repeat that previous step with the other shoulder muscle, this should give you a strong pulling of the shoulder muscles.</string>
    <string name="shrugs">Shrugs</string>
    <string name="shrugs_description">Hold a heavy weighted set of dumbells by your side with your arms staying straight. Now lift the weight up with just your shoulders by moving your shoulders up, hold this position and then lower the shoulders again into position and relax.</string>
    <string name="sits_ups">Sits ups</string>
    <string name="sits_ups_description">Lie your body down flat with your legs bent and your feet flat on the floor, place your hands across your body holding onto your shoulders. Now slowly lift up your upper body whilst keeping your lower body still. When your body has reached right up top then you should lower your body and repeat again.</string>
    <string name="skull_crush">Skull crush</string>
    <string name="skull_crush_description">Sit down on the bench with the weight you are wanting to lift on your knee`s ready. Lie back on the bench and rest the weight on your chest. Lift up the weight to have your arms extended infront of you. Slowly move the weight down using your forearms towards, moving the weight towards your head, then move the weight back into place and repeat.</string>
    <string name="squat">Squat</string>
    <string name="squat_description">Support the bar with both your shoulders and your hands. Lift the bar up off the supports carefully so that the legs are straight, move backwards so that the bar is clear of the supports. Now slowly lower your body by bending your legs with your bottom sticking out, try to get as low as possible and then push with your legs back into a standing position.</string>
    <string name="the_plank">The plank</string>
    <string name="the_plank_description">Start on all fours with your arms spread out flat. Now lift your legs straight and hold your core tight, hold this position for an extended time such as 30 seconds.</string>
    <string name="the_side_plank">The side plank</string>
    <string name="the_side_plank_description">Lie down flat on your side with your hips slightly tilting your upper body so that you may support it on your forearm. Now lift up your body with your hips and hold in position for an extended amount of time.</string>
    <string name="tricep_extensions">Tricep extensions</string>
    <string name="tricep_extensions_description">On the cable machine attach a rope attachment and hold it from behind your back, place yours arms at a 90 degree angle whilst leaning forward. Extend your arms fully forward on a resistant weight to ensure a pullling feeling in your triceps, repeat this.</string>
    <string name="tricep_pull_downs">Tricep pull downs</string>
    <string name="tricep_pull_downs_description">Using a rope attachment hold onto the cable and place your arms at a 90degree angle with enough weight loaded on to give a good resistance. Now straighten out your arms down to feel a strong pulling sensation in your arms. </string>
    <string name="under_arm_chin_ups">Under arm chin ups</string>
    <string name="under_arm_chin_ups_description">Stand with feet flat on the floor and hold onto the bars with your palms facing yourself. Lift your legs off the ground and bend up to a 90 degree algle whilst using a hard grip on the bar. Lift yourself straight up until your chin is level with the bar and then lower yourself back down again.</string>
    <string name="wide_arm_pull_ups">Wide arm pull ups</string>
    <string name="wide_arm_pull_ups_description">Hold the bars in place with your arms stretched wide. Support your body weight whilst your legs can be lifted behind at a 90 degree angle. Now lift your entire body weight up until your chin is at the height of the bar.</string>
    <string name="wide_arm_push_ups">Wide arm push ups</string>
    <string name="wide_arm_push_ups_description">Support your body weight on your hands and your toes and be sure to have your arms extended wide. Now lower your body down towards the floor and then push yourself back up into your original position.</string>
    <string name="zottman_curls">Zottman curls</string>
    <string name="zottman_curls_description">Hold the dumbells by your side facing forward, make sure they are a sutible weight so it is not hurting to hold them in this position. Now lift them up in a curling fashion, aim to have them parrellel to your shoulders. Now turn the dumbells around in your hands so your hands are facing down and slowly move the weight back into the original position.</string>

</resources>